<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://daphne-reed.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-09T20:09:51-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/</id><title type="html">Spurge Laurels</title><subtitle>Petticoated Swashbuckler</subtitle><entry><title type="html">One Year HRT</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/One-Year-HRT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Year HRT" /><published>2017-08-16T12:25:21-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-16T12:25:21-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/One Year HRT</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/One-Year-HRT/">&lt;p&gt;It was one year ago today, that I sat in my doctor’s office, after months of discussions, bloodtests, anxiety, and hope. She wrote out a little scrip, I calmly thanked her, and I took it to a pharmacist, where I handed it over. I expected the world to end at that very moment, but instead she said “come back in an hour”. I was back in 59 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a child, I would often find myself daydreaming of a magic spell, or a pill that would swap my gender from this ill fitting, disassociated, and admittedly awkward male body, to one that my brain seemed to be expecting from the moment I could say the words “boy” or “girl”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here I was, holding those very fucking pills in my own fucking hand, at 34 years old. And I devoured them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year it’s been now, and there hasn’t been a single day that I’ve regretted that decision. Sure, I’ve taken on heaps of sexism, trans/misogyny, and a lot of my friendships and relationships have changed. But I’ve gained many new friends, many new insights, and most importantly, the ability to look fear right in its childish little face, and have the strength to give it the hug it needs to find joy in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/OneYearHRT.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One Year HRT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="transgender" /><summary type="html">It was one year ago today, that I sat in my doctor’s office, after months of discussions, bloodtests, anxiety, and hope. She wrote out a little scrip, I calmly thanked her, and I took it to a pharmacist, where I handed it over. I expected the world to end at that very moment, but instead she said “come back in an hour”. I was back in 59 minutes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Year HRT</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/One-Year-HRT/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Year HRT" /><published>2017-08-16T12:25:21-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-16T12:25:21-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/One Year HRT</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/One-Year-HRT/">&lt;p&gt;It was one year ago today, that I sat in my doctor’s office, after months of discussions, bloodtests, anxiety, and hope. She wrote out a little scrip, I calmly thanked her, and I took it to a pharmacist, where I handed it over. I expected the world to end at that very moment, but instead she said “come back in an hour”. I was back in 59 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a child, I would often find myself daydreaming of a magic spell, or a pill that would swap my gender from this ill fitting, disassociated, and admittedly awkward male body, to one that my brain seemed to be expecting from the moment I could say the words “boy” or “girl”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here I was, holding those very fucking pills in my own fucking hand, at 34 years old. And I devoured them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year it’s been now, and there hasn’t been a single day that I’ve regretted that decision. Sure, I’ve taken on heaps of sexism, trans/misogyny, and a lot of my friendships and relationships have changed. But I’ve gained many new friends, many new insights, and most importantly, the ability to look fear right in its childish little face, and have the strength to give it the hug it needs to find joy in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/OneYearHRT.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One Year HRT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="transgender" /><summary type="html">It was one year ago today, that I sat in my doctor’s office, after months of discussions, bloodtests, anxiety, and hope. She wrote out a little scrip, I calmly thanked her, and I took it to a pharmacist, where I handed it over. I expected the world to end at that very moment, but instead she said “come back in an hour”. I was back in 59 minutes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transition Thus Far</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/Transition-Thus-Far/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transition Thus Far" /><published>2017-07-26T09:12:21-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-26T09:12:21-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/Transition Thus Far</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/Transition-Thus-Far/">&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2017-07-22-11:18:07.png&quot; alt=&quot;8 Momnths&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started on HRT almost one year ago now, and life has been better every day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="transgender" /><category term="photography" /><summary type="html">-</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TransFlagKeyboard</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/TransFlagKeyboard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TransFlagKeyboard" /><published>2017-07-12T09:12:21-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-12T09:12:21-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/TransFlagKeyboard</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/TransFlagKeyboard/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/transboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;TRANSBOARD SQUEEEEEEEE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="computers" /><category term="keyboards" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coming Out At Work</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/Coming-Out-At-Work/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Out At Work" /><published>2017-07-10T13:48:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T13:48:00-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/Coming Out At Work</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/Coming-Out-At-Work/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;coming-out-at-work&quot;&gt;Coming Out At Work&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I sent an email to the whole of my company, stating my intent to transition genders in the workplace.  This is the email:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello friends, extended family, and fellow Vidyardians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a matter of great import to impart upon you, and while I am known for my merry pranks and bouts of tomfoolery, I assure you that this is no prank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found out in spring of 2016 that I am transgender (although, I really have known this since childhood).  This essentially means that my unconscious gender and my expressed (or conscious) gender do not align.  I spent several months with a gender therapist and my doctor, mostly trying to reason my way out of it, or find a way to be happy in my assigned gender (male).  But in the end, we decided to move towards hormone replacement therapy in August of last year.  The impact was almost immediate, and it was immensely positive.  As such, I regret to inform you that my legacy of being Angry Linux Guy is over, and we now enter the era of Pretty-Happy Linux Chick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To elaborate further, I have decided to continue hormone therapy, and move towards a full social transition.  Some of you may have noticed that some changes have already been happening, and over the next few months, many more changes will follow.  These include both physical changes, as well as changes to my attire and presentation.  I’m a practical person, so you will not see much beyond jeans, sneakers, and a snarky T-shirt.  (Although if I find a cute skater dress that has pockets and prints of Tux, the Linux penguin all over it, I reserve the right to wear said skater dress and look totes-adorbz).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This also means that my modes of address (name and gender pronouns) will change.  Presently, my full name is David Robert John Reed, and I will be applying for a legal name change to Daphne Lydia Reed; Daphne being the female equivalent to David.  There’s a lovely backstory about both names that I’m willing to share with anyone who asks. 
My pronouns will also change to she/her.   Many of you have affectionately referred to me as DaveOps for a long time, in fact this nickname was coined during my hiring interview phase!  This can conveniently be replaced with DaphOps, D-Ops, DaphnOps, to taste. 
Also at this time, I will change my designated bathroom as appropriate with my new gender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning for a transition on July 29th, which is my 35th birthday (I know, I don’t look a day over 25!).  After this time, I will no longer be presenting boymode, and will begin presenting in girlmode.  Chances are, you won’t notice a thing, and I hope that you don’t.  But it will be at this time that I will begin politely correcting the use of any incorrect terms, names, or pronouns.  For the first while, I will respond to, and respect the use of both names, and both sets of pronouns.  You will, of course, obtain bonus points for early adoption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond a naming and pronoun change in late July/August, I would hope that our daily interactions do not change, and that everything continues just as it always has.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, comments, positive feedback or messages, please feel free to message me on Slack, or email me.  I have been obsessively researching and educating myself on this subject for the last 16 months, and now possess a wealth of knowledge on this matter;  I am very open to sharing.  I have also included some links to further reading on this subject, if you prefer to self-edify.  You will find them below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sincere apologies to those who are surprised by this news, or offended by learning about this through a company wide email.  My initial intent was to tell everyone in small groups, or one-on-one.  I was able to tell approximately 40 people in this manner, but it proved to be far too emotionally draining to me, and I’ve opted to share this in a team email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to thank everyone who has already shared their positive feedback with me.  I am overwhelmed with joy every single time someone joins me on this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daphne Lydia Reed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2015/02/what-to-do-when-your-colleague-comes-out-as-transgender&quot;&gt;What To Do When Your Colleague Comes Out As Transgender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ed.ted.com/on/lQgoYflA&quot;&gt;Why Pronouns Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.avitale.com/developmentalreview.htm&quot;&gt;The Gender Variant Phenomenon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Coming Out At Work</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Open Letter to the University of Guelph Central Student Association</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/Open_Letter_To_Guelph_CSA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Open Letter to the University of Guelph Central Student Association" /><published>2017-05-23T16:04:23-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-23T16:04:23-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/Open_Letter_To_Guelph_CSA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/Open_Letter_To_Guelph_CSA/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-letter-to-the-university-of-guelph-central-student-association&quot;&gt;Open Letter to the University of Guelph Central Student Association&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the University of Guelph Central Student Association,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chelsea Mulvale, President &lt;br /&gt;
Emily Vance, VP Student Experience&lt;br /&gt;
Becca Cheskes, VP Academic&lt;br /&gt;
Kayla Weiler, VP External&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently came across a shared social media post concerning the removal of Lou Reed’s Walk On The Wild Side from a playlist, based on the perception that the lyrical content contained transphobic ideals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a transgender woman. I can tell you about transphobia, and what it looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lou Reed’s song is in no way transphobic. It merely mentions a story about a transition, and how this person moved to a better life in an accepting community. Lou even uses the appropriate pronouns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not transphobia, this is representation. I would be interested to hold a dialog with those offended by this song, to understand how, and why they were offended. I would also be interested to know if those offended were transgender themselves, or merely being offended on behalf of transgender people. Because in the case of the latter, I would be highly offended to know that someone is being offended on my behalf, and using my identity as a way to censor historically important art and culture. To me, this would be highly insulting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it is important to hold a dialog when someone is offended by something, however a knee-jerk reaction to censor oppositional criticism, or in this case, art and culture, is not the society I wish to live in. You may find, and I predict you will, that your actions to censor and remove this song will erode public trust in your organization. As community leaders, there is no greater damage. I wish to proffer a solution, and would suggest that perhaps a larger and more inclusive process would be in order; engage with local queer community leaders and members, and ask them. Speak to transgender people, with transgender living experience. In the case of racism, or religion, or classism, speak to members of those communities directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it’s okay to edify people that have been offended, and point out that they’re ignorant to the actual message behind the words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daphne Reed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Open Letter to the University of Guelph Central Student Association</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Transness</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/On-Transness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Transness" /><published>2017-05-19T15:24:23-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-19T15:24:23-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/On Transness</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/On-Transness/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-transness&quot;&gt;On Transness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tl;dr : You.  Do.  You.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accepted that I am transgender last spring, almost one year ago to the day of this writing.  It was a whirlwind of self-discovery, and a wild ride of introspection and panic. Of course, I always knew that I was trans, and my earliest memory of desiring girlhood was probably about 5 years old.  But denial is a real prick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I discovered this internal denial, I wasted no time.  A combination of luck, privilege, and sheer willpower, and I had a top-notch therapist, a wonderfully compassionate physician, and a jug of hormones in my hand.  Within weeks, the physical changes and emotional changes were like the best anti-depressants I could have ever asked for; within months, my body and face were closer and closer to what my brain had been expecting all along.  It was getting better and better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I wasn’t wearing makeup.  I wasn’t wearing heels.  I wasn’t wearing a dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wearing jeans, a tshirt, a sports bra, and sneakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another transgender girl in the area seemed to be confused by this.  Her perspective was that there was no point to transitioning genders if I wasn’t going to go full hard femme.  This was very apparent with her question “When do I get to meet Daphne?”, as if transitioning meant that I would become a completely different person.  I’ve always been Daphne, and always will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner was similarly inquisitive, and asked why I would go through all of the hardships of a social transition, just to change my name and gender marker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this outlines the very gender binary that I felt a need to escape; if you’re not 100% male, you must be 100% female.  Early on, my knowledge of transgender folks was minimal, and when I tried to fit my own idea of my own gender into this model, it didn’t work.  So I must not be transgender then, right?  This way of thinking further closeted me, and I ended up taking years longer to realize and come out.  Had I known early on that I could exist on a spectrum, I would have allowed myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However well intentioned and free this spectrum was intended to be, it also serves to provide a grounds for competition between trans folk.  Who passes better; who is more trans.  This can then quickly become a pissing contest where folks who are on HRT feel superior to those who can’t afford it, and those who blend in with cis people feel superior to those who get clocked.  This infighting creates animosity in a community that needs unity and strength.  Again, this is because the spectrum is treated not as a place to exist, but as a progress indicator of how far you’ve progressed in the binary gender model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may one day find me in heels and a dress, perhaps at a wedding, or formal social event.  I’m sure I’ll have fun doing it too.  But until that day, I’ll wear my faded deadmau5 T-shirt, my old boy jeans, and my sneakers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">On Transness
tl;dr : You.  Do.  You.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s ALIVE</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/It's-Alive/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It's ALIVE" /><published>2017-05-02T14:24:23-04:00</published><updated>2017-05-02T14:24:23-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/It's Alive</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/It's-Alive/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-alive&quot;&gt;It’s ALIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few pots of coffee later, and I’m finally rolling with Jekyll.  Coming from Octopress should have made this an easy transition, but it was not for me.  I suppose I could have just started by reading the docs, but I jumped in thinking I would completely understand the framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter!  Here we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I chose Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Static HTML/CSS (&lt;em&gt;security&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I need more Ruby in my life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuck Wordpress&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Markdown is wonderful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary type="html">It’s ALIVE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Necessary Privacy</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/necessary-privacy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Necessary Privacy" /><published>2014-02-11T07:18:16-05:00</published><updated>2014-02-11T07:18:16-05:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/necessary-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/necessary-privacy/">&lt;p&gt;15 years ago, I held the position that governments and technology providers were not only able to, but were &lt;em&gt;actively&lt;/em&gt; monitoring data communications through several dragnet operations.  Dismissed as a conspiracy theorist left me with very few people to share gpg keys for email encryption; not that this stopped me from storing my information encrypted, hiding my online tracks, and other actions that furthered the perception that I was a bit paranoid.  A typical conversation on this topic usually led to the question “what do you have to hide”?   I’ve never had anything incriminating to hide, and it was never about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was about control over my own personal information, where it ended up, who had access, who was rewriting it, and who was selling it.  It was also about being labeled something I wasn’t, just because of an acquaintance or affiliation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the time that I started really taking privacy seriously, I pulled out my soapbox and started preaching to anyone within earshot usually to their chagrin.  I observed that most people considered their privacy to be a right, and placed trust in the authorities to regulate and manage any of the information collected about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today.
A simple civilian-accessible search on someone’s name can get you emails, phone numbers, addresses, current and past employers, images, purchases on eBay.  Using this information can further reveal more and more information until an entire profile is built on this person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or you can just add them Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the problem with all of this information being collected and processed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This data is persistent; it will not be deleted&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The data is only good if it’s properly related to other data from the same person; processes are in place to ensure the validity, although there is no guarantee that your data isn’t linked  erroneously&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are no regulations or laws saying that all of your data must be accessible to you (even through FOI/FIPPA)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are no mechanisms in place to opt out of this collection&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what happens when the analytics engine fails?  When we’re talking about big data, we’re talking about a staggering amount of information.  No single person or group could manually sift through this data and draw correlations.  A program or process handles that work load.  History has taught us that programs and processes have bugs.  Suddenly, you may find yourself on a list among sex offenders, political dissidents, or worse.  Just because you had a common friend with a wanted criminal, and your grandmother’s computer had been infected with a botnet that was being used to distribute anti-government propaganda.  &lt;strong&gt;_There is no one you can call to get this association removed.  _&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can you do to prevent this in the first place? You can become translucent, obfuscate, and protect.  Starting with your web browser and email, encrypt everything that you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTTPS for web connections, and GnuPG for email&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t bother trying to encrypt to keep the NSA out, just try and keep data mining apps and scripts from hauling off your personal data&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try not to leave tracks by requesting that sites do not track you, turn off scripts with NoScript, disable incoming ads, and don’t accept or store third party cookies&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Shred your bills and other hard copies with personal information&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Don’t give your postal code or personal details to merchants&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You cannot escape the data dragnet entirely, without going completely off the grid.  But you can minimize the chances of a disastrous theft of identity by corporate interests, governmental bodies, or other types of nefarious criminal organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>dave</name></author><category term="big data" /><category term="privacy" /><category term="security" /><summary type="html">15 years ago, I held the position that governments and technology providers were not only able to, but were actively monitoring data communications through several dragnet operations.  Dismissed as a conspiracy theorist left me with very few people to share gpg keys for email encryption; not that this stopped me from storing my information encrypted, hiding my online tracks, and other actions that furthered the perception that I was a bit paranoid.  A typical conversation on this topic usually led to the question “what do you have to hide”?   I’ve never had anything incriminating to hide, and it was never about that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASA Failover</title><link href="https://daphne-reed.io/asa-failover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASA Failover" /><published>2013-07-08T22:42:10-04:00</published><updated>2013-07-08T22:42:10-04:00</updated><id>https://daphne-reed.io/asa-failover</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://daphne-reed.io/asa-failover/">&lt;p&gt;Setting up a failover between Cisco ASA units proved to be far simpler than I anticipated, and a very useful technique if you value the availability and potential load-balancing it has to offer.   In the example below, I will demonstrate an Active/Standby configuration, which does not allow for load-balanced operation.  For load balancing, you will need to run in Active/Active configuration and you will need to configure them in context mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/img/oldblog/asa.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/oldblog/asa-210x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;Topology&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our topology will include 2 ASA 5520 units, ASA4 and ASA5.  After you’ve configured your basic ASA operation, we’ll want to configure our interfaces. The difference between a failover setup and a normal setup is the standby address.  The IP used for a standby address will end up being the address of the secondary unit while it’s in standby mode.  If the secondary unit goes active, it will then assume the first address.  So, the configuration is set on ASA4 is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;interface Ethernet0/0
 nameif OUTSIDE
 security-level 0
 ip address 10.0.0.1 255.255.255.0 standby 10.0.0.2

interface Ethernet0/1
 nameif INSIDE
 security-level 100
 ip address 172.16.0.1 255.255.255.0 standby 172.16.0.2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once set, enable the interfaces and test that they’re operational.  Next, we’re going to configure the failover itself, and then configure interface ethernet0/3 as our dedicated failover link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, shut down ethernet0/3 on ASA4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;conf t
int e0/3
shut
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, configure ASA4 for the following failover directives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;failover
failover lan unit primary
failover lan interface FAIL Ethernet0/3
failover interface ip FAIL 192.168.1.1 255.255.255.0 standby 192.168.1.2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will set ASA4 as the primary unit, creating an interface named FAIL and attaching it to physical interface Ethernet0/3 on 192.168.1.1.  We can leave ethernet0/3 shutdown for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we want to configure ASA5 with the same interface configuration, only in reverse:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;interface Ethernet0/0
 nameif OUTSIDE
 security-level 0
 ip address 10.0.0.2 255.255.255.0 standby 10.0.0.1

interface Ethernet0/1
 nameif INSIDE
 security-level 100
 ip address 172.16.0.2 255.255.255.0 standby 172.16.0.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we configure the secondary failover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;failover
failover lan unit secondary
failover lan interface FAIL Ethernet0/3
failover interface ip FAIL 192.168.1.1 255.255.255.0 standby 192.168.1.2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then finally, we can enable e0/3 on both ASA4 and ASA5 with&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;conf t 
int e0/3
no shut
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, you should see some console logging data showing synchronization between the ASA units, as they negotiate configuration data and enable the sync link on e0/3.  Once complete, you will find the following output from running a ‘show failover’ on each host:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;ASA4&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;# show failover
Failover On
Failover unit &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Primary&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
Failover LAN Interface: FAIL Ethernet0/3 (up)
Unit Poll frequency 1 seconds, holdtime 15 seconds
Interface Poll frequency 5 seconds, holdtime 25 seconds
Interface Policy 1
Monitored Interfaces 2 of 250 maximum
Version: Ours 8.0(2), Mate 8.0(2)
Last Failover at: 00:00:06 UTC Nov 30 1999
        This host: Primary - Active
                Active time: 3135 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;OUTSIDE (10.0.0.1)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;INSIDE (172.16.0.1)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                slot 1: empty
        Other host: Secondary - Standby Ready
                Active time: 0 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;OUTSIDE (10.0.0.2)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;INSIDE (172.16.0.2)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                slot 1: empty





&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;ASA4&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;# show failover
Failover On
Failover unit &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Secondary&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;
Failover LAN Interface: FAIL Ethernet0/3 (up)
Unit Poll frequency 1 seconds, holdtime 15 seconds
Interface Poll frequency 5 seconds, holdtime 25 seconds
Interface Policy 1
Monitored Interfaces 2 of 250 maximum
Version: Ours 8.0(2), Mate 8.0(2)
Last Failover at: 00:00:01 UTC Nov 30 1999
        This host: Secondary - Standby Ready
                Active time: 0 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt; OUTSIDE (10.0.0.2)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;INSIDE (172.16.0.2)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                slot 1: empty
        Other host: Primary - Active
                Active time: 3138 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;OUTSIDE (10.0.0.1)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                  Interface &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;INSIDE (172.16.0.1)&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;: Normal
                slot 1: empty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve emboldened a few key points in the failover output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that the hostname is the same on both ASA units.  This is because they’re essentially a single logical entity now, with one unit acting as the primary, and syncing data to the secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ll also notice that the primary host has the x.x.x.1 addresses for its interfaces, while the secondary has the x.x.x.2 addresses.  Watch what happens next…&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test our failover, log into ASA4, and type “no failover active”, which will tell the active failover host to drop to standby mode.  &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; type “no failover”, as this will turn off failover altogether, and this would be bad on a production box.   You’ll see in the output of “show failover” that the IP addresses of the INSIDE and OUTSIDE interfaces have swapped between the Primary and Secondary hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASA4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This host: Primary - Standby Ready
                Active time: 3552 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface OUTSIDE (10.0.0.2): Normal (Waiting)
                  Interface INSIDE (172.16.0.2): Normal (Waiting)
                slot 1: empty
        Other host: Secondary - Active
                Active time: 25 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface OUTSIDE (10.0.0.1): Normal (Waiting)
                  Interface INSIDE (172.16.0.1): Normal (Waiting)
                slot 1: empty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASA5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;This host: Primary - Standby Ready
                Active time: 3552 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface OUTSIDE (10.0.0.2): Normal (Waiting)
                  Interface INSIDE (172.16.0.2): Normal (Waiting)
                slot 1: empty
        Other host: Secondary - Active
                Active time: 25 (sec)
                slot 0: empty
                  Interface OUTSIDE (10.0.0.1): Normal (Waiting)
                  Interface INSIDE (172.16.0.1): Normal (Waiting)
                slot 1: empty
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarize, we have created a configuration with two modes, active and standby.  Then we’ve created a link between our two devices, over which they synchronize their configuration and communicate their states.  In the event that the Primary device fails, the Secondary device already has both a working replicated configuration, but also a copy of open connection states in memory.  This allows for a clean cutover with no packet loss.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="firewall" /><category term="network" /><summary type="html">Setting up a failover between Cisco ASA units proved to be far simpler than I anticipated, and a very useful technique if you value the availability and potential load-balancing it has to offer.   In the example below, I will demonstrate an Active/Standby configuration, which does not allow for load-balanced operation.  For load balancing, you will need to run in Active/Active configuration and you will need to configure them in context mode.</summary></entry></feed>
